PHILLIPE ALVES

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

INFO

ADDRESS

Melbourne, Australia

PHONE

0474-851-747

EMAIL

phillipe.alves@gmail.com

LINKS

Linkedin

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

• • • • •

English

• • • • •

Spanish; Castilian

• • • •

German

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

French

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Italian

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

PROFILE

Hi, I'm Phillipe - a software engineer with a background as a chef, lawyer and musician. For the past ten years I have lived and worked in cities around the world including New York, Berlin, Montreal, Melbourne and Brasilia. My passion to learn about different cultures has led me to experience a huge range of different working environments, collaborating with others in fast-paced settings using multiple languages to communicate.

I'm all about transforming passion into value. As a hungry learner with a keen attention to detail, I take joy in crafting elegant, simple solutions for the problems that I solve. I leverage my mature work ethic and refined people skills to help bring out the best in every team collaboration I am part of.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Chef

2008 — 2020

I started cooking because I love the way food brings people together, but also because I fell in love with the creative process. Starting my journey as a pastry chef, I innovated on classic pastry recipes to create my own techniques and presentations. Here, I developed my sense of visual aesthetics and time management skills. Later, as a chef in different cities around the world, I learned how to help optimize team collaboration; creating a positive working dynamic in high-pressure environments.

Music Producer / Musician

2002 — 2020

Music has a special place in my heart as a way to connect people. Over the past two decades I've worked as a professional musician- as a lead singer, playing different instruments and producing music electronically. Because of my experience performing in different cities, I am highly confident with public speaking and presentation. I love composing, directing a band and sparking joyful energy in a crowd.

Law analyst

2003 - 2008

The most important personal quality I developed during my time in law was diligence, as I worked hard to build a strong body of knowledge around the rules and parameters relevant to the discipline. Five years working in that environment

developed my ability to think logically, academically and philosophically. I became a Chief of Department in the Ministry of Justice in Brasilia, the capital of Brazil.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering, General Assembly

Melbourne, Australia

2020 - 2020

Hospitality, IESB

Brasília, Brazil

2008 - 2010

Law, IESB Brasilia, Brazil

2002 - 2007